ANDRÉ MENDES

Backend Software Engineer

City/State/Country Araraguara/SP/Brazil

WhatsApp/Telegram +55 65 98117 3729; andre@mendesc.com

Education

Computer Science Bachelor [2009 - 2013] UFMT - incomplete

Synopsis

Over 8 years of experience developing backend software systems for web applications. I am passionate about Typescript, NestJS and software development in general. I have experience developing and maintaining solutions on client-focused software deployed on the cloud.

I've got excellent communication skills and I am a good team member. I can handle incidents, write reports and documentation. Deep knowledge of automating tasks, creating and consuming APIs, talking either REST or GraphQL, writing unit and integration tests, doing web-scraping and making Robotic Software Automation.

I am a Free Software and Open-source Contributor and have experience with Amazon Cloud (EC2, S3, Lambda, SQS, RDS and more) and Azure Cloud. I have experience working with international clients on overseas teams and can read/write/speak in English and Portuguese. Good Linux knowledge

Career Summary

The Kraft Heinz Company - Senior Backend Engineer - (2022/April -Present)

Backend systems for a global social-network. Heavy use of Typescript, NestJS, Postgres, Azure, Jest, GraphQL and more.

Qelp/Sykes/Sitel - Senior Backend Engineer - (2021/July - 2022/April)

Creating and keeping apps handling millions monthly users for Telco clients on AWS, Nodejs, Serverless, PHP and Linux

Suthub - Tech Lead (6 backend devs + P.O. team) - Python (2020/Oct - 2021/July)

Analysis, Development, Testing and Cloud deployment of features for a product bought by a top financial institution.

OpenSource:

<u>HaxeFlixel</u> (https://github.com/HaxeFlixel): Adapted few demos to make them work on apple devices
Bozorun (https://github.com/dremendes/bozorun) Created a politically-themed, open-source infinite-runner

Freelancer: Full-stack web developer [mid 2018 ~ mid 2020] - LAMP stack with Laravel

Bltree – Full-stack web developer [2016 ~2017] – alow.com.br

Analysis and development of components using PHP 7, Symfony 3, Javascript, Mysgl and Deployment automation

Trinix – Full-stack web developer [November 2014 ~ November 2015] –

Development of front and backend components using custom PHP framework. Deployment automation

Doingcast – Full-stack web developer and co-founder [2013/august ~ 2014/july]

Built system to analyze computer usage for performance metrics and surveillance using Python + Django

Intoo – Full-stack web developer [2013/march ~ 2013/august]

Built core system for fintech startup on AWS EC2 / S3 on PHP + Silex + HTML5 + AngularJS

Uniorka – Internship in Systems Analysis [2012/april ~ 2013/march